RESUME

Sebastian Kovacs

9/5 Dawson Street, Newcastle, NSW 2300 0432 365 389, sebkovacs@gmail.com

For the last two years I have been completing the Master of Architecture course, whilst working part time in three jobs: Sales and Marketing at Livetools, Architect Assistant at Jason Topic Architecture, and Personal Training with my own business. At present, I have 10 weeks of the Masters degree left.

My goal is to make a career in development and I am looking to work hard in an opportunity that will allow me to advance towards a development management role.

I am seeking to work in a dynamic high tempo environment and to be working with people. I always have an attitude to learn and be progressing. I have diverse experience and am quick to learn and to adapt.

EDUCATION

- Masters of Architecture 2022, University of Newcastle
- Bachelor Degree Architecture 2011, University of Newcastle
- Contract Administration course (as past of Masters program)
- Bob Anderson Property Development Course 2018
- Property Development Institute Course 2018
- Google Digital Marketing & Analytics Courses

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Jason Topic Architecture: Aug 2017-Present

Architect Assistant

Architecture firm with diverse projects across luxury residential, multi-residential, commercial, industrial, sports facilities, education and child care.

- Resolve design solutions to meet project brief and within relevant regulations, legislation and codes
- Concept design and feasibility analysis
- Work on multi concurrent projects
- Prepare and Lodge Development Applications, both autonomously and in an assisting role
- Knowledge of NCCA, LEPs, DCPs, SEPPs, SSD, Environmental Planning and Assessment Act 1979
- Assist preparation of SEE reports and Detailed specifications
- Coordinate documents with project relevant consultants
- Preparation of construction documents and CC application
- 3D renders and marketing material

Livetools: May 2017 - Present

Marketing and Sales

- External sales generate leads, schedule meetings and make presentations (typically to General Managers, Directors or Senior Managers).
- Listen and ask accurate questions to effectively understand customer problems and needs
- Maintain a high level of communication, face to face and via phone and email
- Keep excellent records and documentation of all interactions, quotes and transactions
- Work in a small business high tempo environment
- Marketing via social media, google, SEO / SEM, exhibitions
- Assist and/or manage the organisation and execution of exhibiting at trade shows
- Work effectively in a team
- Quote and Negotiate deals

RESUME Sebastian Kovacs 1

Essential Media Australia, Louisiana Flip 'n' Move, TV series, USA

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017 (Short term contract)

Creative department Assistant (Design & Construction Management)

- High intensity Project duration of 16 weeks to complete 20 houses for film production
- Assist in design procurement and management of multiple construction teams to deliver complete houses on time for filming (time critical to entire season - no flexibility)
- · Assisted in the development & execution of unique design briefs
- Management and procurement of materials & products for the renovation, fitout & staging of houses
- Assisted in management and oversight of construction teams for quality control & work schedule
- Assisted in managing conflicts through regular clear communication with construction teams

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present

Newcastle Fitness Bootcamp

- Lead and manage larger groups
- 5-20 people group fitness session
- Planning and organisation of cross training & military style training
- Implement science based training with focus around metal & physical health & wellbeing

2018 - Present

Flame Storytelling

Co-founder and co-director

- Started a live storytelling event with Shea Evans, with the goal for community building & personal development
- Collaborative leadership
- Organise and manage storytellers and other team members
- Organise venue, set a dates for events and 'make it happen' always working under pressure
- Market the event through multiple channels
- Has been highly successful and fully sold out the last 3 events
- Excellent learning opportunity managing people, expectations, negotiation and quick problem solving

Paul Hickson Builder: Apr 2017 - Dec 2017

Carpentry

- Ex Master Builders Newcastle President
- Experience working on Luxury / high spec residential projects
- Work as offsider with main carpenter participating in all activities across all stages of construction
- Interpret and build correctly from plans and specifications to a very high standards

HAYS: Nov 2016 - Apr 2017

Construction Labour

North Construction: Opal Hillside aged Care Facility \$35 million, Bishop Tyrrell Anglican College \$5.3 million **Core Project:** Saint Francis Xavier Catholic Church

- Worked across various project stages of commercial construction in multiple sectors
- Assist head contractor in working alongside all subcontractors; resulting in an increased awareness
 of roles, functions, time frames and potential issues
- Developed insight into the complexities of construction, site management and risk in construction
- Observed the impact of poor project planning and design decisions that resulted in time delays, defect costs, variations & reduced construction efficiency (time)

RESUME Sebastian Kovacs 2

2016

Australian Army: Special Forces Training Center

Commando Training and Selection Course Not selected, recommend reapply

2011-2015

Army Reserve

Infantry

Various short & long duration exercises, no deployments Most Improved Junior Leader 2012 - 2/17 RNSWR Best Soldier 2012 - Infantry Employment Training course Fittest Soldier 2012 - Infantry Employment Training course

Self Employed Personal Trainer

SOFTWARE

- High proficiency with Vectorworks
- Proficiency with Revit, ArchiCAD
- Proficient with Microsoft Office, Google office suite (excel, word, powerpoint)
- Proficient with Adobe creative suite (Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, Premiere Pro)
- Capable with both Estate Master & Devfeas software

REFEREE'S

Arthur Alexiou (Director) - 0413 300 198

Livetools

Jason Topic (Director / Principal) - 0411 488 282

Jason Topic Architect

Paul Hickson (Director) - 0408 684 456

Paul Hickson Builder

Shea Evans (Co-founder) - 0431 100 194

Newcastle Flame

RESUME Sebastian Kovacs 3